# Serguei Ossokine, Ph.D

# Data Engineer

♦ https://sergeiossokine.github.io ☑ serguei.ossokine@tutanota.com 🛅 Serguei Ossokine🗘 SergeiOssokine

Data professional with 7+ years of experience in designing and implementing data pipelines, performing complex data analysis, and developing scientific software. Strong background in Python, SQL, and cloud computing.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Scientific Programmer at Max Planck Institute for Gravitational Physics ♥ Potsdam, Germany Jul 2019 - Jul 2023

- Designed and implemented an end-to-end ETL data processing Python pipeline to incorporate data from multiple sources, improving efficiency by over 200%.
- Spearheaded the development of state-of-the-art code Python code to model gravitational waves from binary black hole systems, improving efficiency and accuracy 10x.
- Led the creation of a Python framework for automatic parameter selection in data analysis, decreasing time to production
- Performed full Bayesian statstical analysis and model selection for headline publications.
- Created impactful scientific visualizations exceeding 400k views and garnering media attention from outlets like Scientific American.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams in scientific collaboration spread across the globe. Mentored undergraduate and graduate students.

**Postdoctoral Scholar** at Max Planck Institute for Gravitational Physics **♥ Potsdam, Germany** Sep 2015 - Jul 2019

- **Developed an R code** to compute equilibrium solutions for boson stars, **enabling the first comparison** of binary boson star simulations with different numerical codes.
- Contributed to large-scale C/C++ scientific code-bases for numerical modelling gravitational waves, including
  parallelized HPC codes, such as LALSuite and Spectral Einstein Code, with the results used in >50 of publications.
- Created a codebase to benchmark the accuracy of gravitational wave models, streamlining comparisons of different models.

# **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Astronomy and Astrophysics at University of Toronto

Sep 2010 - Aug 2015

Thesis: Modelling precessing binary black hole systems

M.Sc. in Astronomy and Astrophysics at University of Toronto

Sep 2009 - Aug 2010

BSc in Astronomy and Astrophysics at University of Toronto

Sep 2005 - Aug 2009

# **SKILLS**

ammin	

Python | R | SQL | C/C++ | bash | Fortran |

Javascript

## **Data Analysis & ML**

Statistical modeling | Bayesian methods | numpy | scipy | pandas | scikit-learn | pytorch | tensorflow | MLFlow | W&B

# **Data Engineering**

PostgreSQL | Airflow | dlt

## Cloud computing

AWS | Terraform | CloudFormation

#### Tools

Git | CI/CD tools such as Github Actions, etc | Docker | Linux | Office

## **LANGUAGES**

English

Native speaker

**Russian** Native speaker French Intermediate

#### German

Beginner